# Javad Adib





github.com/MrJavadAdib



# Senior Full Stack Engineer

Professional software engineer with 14+ years of experience in developing cutting-edge web solutions. A lover of microservice architecture due to the freedom of technology and scalability. Collaboration with 50+ of specialists and teamwork led to the acquisition of valuable insight, particularly on e-commerce. Open-source enthusiast.

🔀 mr.javad.adib@gmail.com



+98-935-726-9759



🔾 Iran

# **Professional Experience**

### **Lead Full Stack Engineer**

Jibres Full-time

(2 years 8 months) 12/2019 - present

- Implemented an integrated cloud eCommerce solution for 1,200+ businesses containing website, app, POS software, CRM, CMS, accounting software, ticketing system, and form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced the new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated the native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

Tech Stack PHP, RESTful API, Redis, MySQL, JavaScript, Gradle, Git, NodeJS, Express, Vanilla JS, Sass, Tailwind, PHPUnit, Docker, Nginx, Scrum, Jira, OWASP, CORS, PWA, CLI, XML, JSON, YAML, SaaS, SEO

#### Senior Full Stack Engineer

Azvir Full-time

(2 years 4 months) 09/2017 - 12/2019

- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.
- Analyzed and database design from scratch. Design 150+ SPA functional modules with server-side rendering technique.

Tech Stack PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Gulp, HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, Sass, SSR, Nginx, Git, Scrumban, Trello, JSON, Twig, AJAX

## Senior Full Stack Developer

Sarshomar Full-time (2 years 4 months) 06/2015 - 09/2017

- Spearheaded the 15 members' cross-functional team, and launched a product that earned about 1M users in just a month.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

Tech Stack PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Grunt, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Apache, GitHub, Kanban, Trello, JSON, AJAX, A/B Testing

#### Computer Lecturer

Teacher Part-time (11 years 4 months) 06/2006 - 09/2017

- Taught 2,000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, and private classes.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to an acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers from around the world.

Taught HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, WordPress, C, C++, OOP, SOLID, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, VBA, Apache, Nginx, Git, SEO

#### Software Developer

Mixa Full-time

(3 years 11 months) 08/2011 - 06/2015

Developed a cloud archiving solution that saves +1M docs annually and avoids wasting several tons of paper.

Tech Stack PHP, C#, JavaScript, MySQL, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Git, CLI, Bash, FTP, SOAP, Apache, Memcached, AJAX

#### UI/UX WordPress Developer

Freelancer Freelance

(3 years) 09/2008 - 08/2011

Designed and developed 40+ WordPress websites with HTML5 and CSS3, improved user experience, achieved a high SEO rank.

Tech Stack PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, CSS, cPanel, Apache

## Education

## M.S. in Information Technology Management

Azad University Part-time, ABD

Expected in 2022

## **B.S. in Computer Software Engineering**

Azad University Part-time

2014

# Skills

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP

**Language** C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Bash, Python

Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML

Distributed Cache Redis, Memcached

Web Service SOAP, REST API, GraphQL

Web Framework Express.js, Laravel, Symfony, Vue.js

Front-end JS Library Vanilla JS, jQuery, Alpine.js, React

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Version Control System Git, GitHub, GitLab

Test Driven Development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Infrastructure Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, RabbitMQ, AWS, S3

Software Development Methodology Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Microsoft Office Specialist Excel, Access, PowerPoint, VBA

Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma

Miscellaneous Cloud Development, RDBMS, QA, Analysis, SaaS,

Object Orientated, Crwal, Maintenance, CORS, NPM, Composer,

PWA, XHTML, AJAX, SCSS, LEMP, LAMP, CLI, SEO, OOD, SOLID

# Awards and Honors

#### Membership

Iran's National Elites Foundation

2013

#### Silver Medal

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business

2009

#### Medallion for Excellence

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

2008

# Volunteer work

## Software Solutions for Business - Expert

WorldSkills

(5 years 3 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

Tutored and trained three talents who have won silver and two bronze medals in national competitions; held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

## Languages

English Fluent C1

**Persian** Native